hello and welcome everybody I margin and
today we're going to be doing a tutorial
on how to manage a remote and local
repository using get Dewey now get is
just a simple program that allows you to
manage all your paws Tory's the gooey
factor of it is simply a graphical user
interface that it makes it quite simple
to use compared to using the command
line so the first thing we're going to
want to do is set up our remote
repository and to do that you're going
to need need to create an account with
the bit bucket for this you can go to
bitbucket org all the links in this
video will be in the description also
there's a link there to that you simply
just put the username email and password
it's a free side once you've done that
you can log in and you're going to come
into a to a page similar to this this is
your dashboard as you can see here I
have four repositories currently on my
account that i am working on but what
you're going to do to create a new
repository is going to go over here to
create and you're just going to click
there it's gonna bring you to screen
like this what you're going to do now is
enter a name for your repository you can
see I have a couple from the past here
we're just going to name this one get
tutorial before I can spell that'd be
great
I used through a quick description in
there if you'd like so we're going to
say how to use get if you click this
here I all it does is affect whether
someone needs to put in a password or
not to work with the remote people also
we are going to leave this on just so
that only we can allow people to user
repository if they have the password
again the other settings here you will
not have to worry about
we're just doing a simple explanation
how to use get so it is not that
important here in language you can
choose which codebase you're using that
there's a long list of different things
you can use you do not have to select
one but it is helpful and it will help
you when you're working on bitbucket
here so we're just gonna go ahead and
select Ravitz a codebase i usually
working but feel free to use what ever
you are using
and then just go ahead and click create
repository and here you are you're at
the dashboard of your get tutorial but
as you can see there's nothing here we
go to our source
nothing is here it's asking us to our
first commit it's just an empty
repository it's just there it's set up
so that we can use it now so we're going
to do all we need to do using Google's
going to hear click i have an existing
project and this URL right here is what
you're going to want to use okay all
this is https colon slash slash your
username at bucket . org slash your user
name / title of the repository place any
spaces with ashes . get ok but if you
just go right here you'll be able to
access that very easily and so now we
are done with bitbucket . work we're
going to go ahead and download get going
to want to go to get dash
scmp.com this is the homepage forget and
as you can see here just on the right
side there is a download for windows
there's also different village for linux
as well as Mac we're going to do windows
for today
that's what i'm using we're gonna get as
you're going to get this file here you
just click Save and that will download
onto your computer once it's done
downloading it's right there on my
desktop you're going to want to go ahead
and double click that and it's going to
bring up the install page for first you
may get the skirt security one and just
hit run and if you get any other ones
just hit yes and it's gonna bring up the
setup wizard here so all you need to do
on the screen is hit next and next again
here you the only you need to make sure
that's changed is that additional icons
is selected all that's going to do is
toss the shortcut on your desktop and
click Launch so it's easier to access
then you're going to hit next until we
get all the way through don't have to
worry about in these things and we'll
just wait for the install to finish here
right now we're going to uncheck view
release notes it's not necessary that
you view them if you do have a reason
for you
absolutely of the power to but we're
just going to go ahead and skip that for
now I was going to do is you're going to
get to get gooey the shortcut on your
desktop just pull over the git bash one
here as well so these are the two that
are going to show up on your desktop
we're not going to get bachelors put
that away for now we're just going to
stick with gooeys it's easier to
understand and much easier to work with
go ahead and double-click that on this
page will open up here this is the
google homepage you have three options
create a new repository which is going
to create a local repository on this
computer
the second option is clone an existing
repository and once I what that will do
is clone a relative repository from
another location whether it be remote or
locally so that's good for if you have
other people that would like to use your
programmer sorry out that would like to
use your repository they'll be able to
clone it and work on and on their
machine and open existing repository was
to open a repository that you have
stored on your computer
generally if you've already open them
you'll have an open recent repository
which is much easier to use usually just
click on that brings me to my repository
saves me a little bit of time so the
first thing we need to do is we're going
to create a new repository so we have a
remote repository here on bitbucket but
no way is that connected yet to our
computer
ok so we're going to first create a new
repository and we're going to put choose
the director that goes in just so for
ease of access here we're going to put
it on the desktop so we're just going to
go ahead and select
whoops we're going to actually go up
here to desktop select desktop
ok it's going to put in the directory
first we're actually just going to add a
new folder named they're also not having
this is not splattered with us up so
we'll call it get tutorial and just go
ahead and create our click create in
here is the screen for your repository
to be easily be resized to whatever you
need to be in here let me just drag the
folder here there's the folder that we
just created understand my second
daughter here so if we open that up
there it is
you can see that there's a hidden folder
called . get this is the folder that it
uses to understand all the changes and
work with your repository so that's how
you know it's your local repository
there now that we have our local
repository we're going to want to
connect that the remote repository so
we're going to do is we're going to the
remote tab here we're gonna add
selection so you can choose a name the
name is not Todd does not truly matter
too much so if you want you can use a
descriptive name such as tutorial remote
location or mota repo but generally what
I just go with is I just name it
origin I'd simple and I know that that's
where it's coming from and then the
location you're going to put that URL
for the remote repository that was the
one we got off this page right here just
go ahead and grab that you just copy it
and you're going to go ahead and paste
it right there in the location and
simply have to click Add what it's going
to do the fetch immediately just means
it's going to fetch from it right away
nothing there's that's fine so just add
it you're going to get this little
screen here it will prompt you for a
password
just toss in the password you use to set
up your account that's what it's gonna
be prompting you for and then it's going
to show you that six success which means
we are now connected
ok now our repositories are connected so
we're going to go ahead and we're going
to create a new file in here as if
you're working in our repository so
we're going to create our readme file to
the first file you create groups made a
bit of a spelling mistake then we fix
that perfect go in and we're going to
say okay I'm get tutorial perfect to
save up the file close it down now we
have a new file so now what we have to
do is you have to make sure that the
that get knows that's there so we're
going to do is you're going to click
rescan going to check for any files that
have been changed since the last commit
so you can see the readme file is there
but now we're going to want to stage
those files so that we can commit them
so it's going to ask you to stage one on
track file
yes we do want to do that now you're
gonna say it's in the stage that's
what's gonna be committed if you hit
commit a crime so next they want to do
is you always in a message with your
commit so I always click sign off here
and what that does it's going to sound
show that it's signed off by so-and-so
with such an email so i just change that
to my name and my email and we're also
going to toss a message in there that
says we added the readme file okay just
so if anyone else looking at repository
they know what we did on this commit and
then you simply hit commit and welcome
it does is that's going to commit
locally on the computer so it saved
locally on the repository the next thing
we need to do now is we need that now
need to change it on the remote
repository so if we go look locally it's
there but if we go to remote and we go
to our source tab here you're going to
see that it's still empty
okay so we need to go ahead and push
that up to the remote repository so go
ahead and hit click push going to see
whatever branch you're working on more
work on master so select that USA which
destinations going to its remote origins
what we need that before
if you have more to be shown there and
then you're just going to go ahead and
click push it's going to prompt you for
the password
so go ahead and type in the same
password you use for your account again
and there you go you can see the
successful show you what's been pushed
up 422 bites of the file and that's
always pushed wonderful success now we
just go ahead and close that wonderful
and now if we go ahead and refresh
refresh the remote repository here you
can see there's our there's a readme
file and that's the information that's
in it
we're just going to go ahead and change
it here so we're going to go ahead and
just put the point 01 you can just
change some things through dad bitbucket
so we're going to commit that so that
things have been changed and it's going
to show you hear that on this commit we
just added the point of one that's
what's been changed wonderful and what
we can do now is we're going to go
remote fetch from origin so that's a
remote repository we're going to click
that it's going to bring up the fetch
screen and it's going to ask for
password again type in your password you
go and it's going to show you that
something's been fetched 142 success
there's been a change there now what we
need to do is if you look here nothing's
changed
this is because we've just finished the
changes we haven't applied them to our
local repository to do that you're going
to do emerge you want to stretch to and
want to go into local emergency origin
master we're going to want to merge that
so what that's going to do is it's going
to apply the changes to our local
repository that you can see the changes
there and it was a success
so now if we go down into get tutorial
here open up and open the remaining
they're going to see it's changed to be
. all one so what we're going to do next
here is we're going to clone an existing
repository so anyone working on your
project that needs repository and their
computers going to select this here
clone existing repository you're going
to choose the source location again
where you want to store that repository
so we can just go ahead and select our
remote repository location that we had
before such as where the repos coming
from can be a local location as well but
you're going to give your
multiplication of someone they'll put it
in there and then we're going to select
our desktop again for our target
directory which is where it's going to
go and we're going to call it get
tutorial to come and then you just hit
clone it's going to take a second here
it's going to prompt you for three sets
of passwords all the same password you
just have to do it a couple times here
there's the second one and finally the
third one here and then we're going to
come up with our get tutorial too and
it's not going to be set up on the
desktop under the firearms of the file
folder to get tutorial to just pull it
over here
there it is and there's the readme file
as we changed it before up on the remote
repository wonderful so we're just going
to create a new file here that we are
just working on and decide that we don't
want to put on a more positive even
called error . text I'm just gonna put
some random order to submit which closed
that down and we're gonna save it
wonderful
so Eric text now if we reschedule we're
going to see that that's something we
don't want on our repository we've made
an error so what you're going to do is
going to stage that change anything in
the green here I is what can be reset
what can be deleted so if you need to
eat some you go ahead and staged it
you're going to go to branch and reset
the branch reset you can see everything
that was in the green there is removed
you have to stage first also want to
leave it if we go back into our tutorial
here you're going to see that file is no
longer there so it's been reset so let's
say you're working on a code file and
you add 10 20 lines of code you realize
you made a mistake you can simply rescan
stage and then reset and that's going to
raise only the lines of code you changed
that's going to help you with your
project
ok on PEEP pocket here there's a few
useful things you can see the commits
what we've done you see which one to
commit so far we've added the readme
file and edit it online using the pocket
and commit to anyone you'll be able to
see who's done it and the message that
they left with it as well as you can
click on and see exactly what has been
changed
ok so bitbucket organs very useful
for this very useful for to contract
what's been done so make scenario you
very easily go back find it and fix it
as well as on your overview time you're
gonna have a my newsfeed here that will
show what's been done as well so it's
always good to keep an eye on that
anyways thank you very much for watching
the tutorial wish you guys the best of
luck with your projects in the future
and you guys have any questions or
comments please leave them in the
comment section below and I'll do my
best to get back to this
good luck using it